<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>akent.org</title>
    <link>https://akent.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on akent.org</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 20:01:55 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://akent.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Photobooth with Nikon wireless DSLR camera sync</title>
      <link>https://akent.org/posts/photobooth-with-nikon-wireless-camera/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 20:01:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akent.org/posts/photobooth-with-nikon-wireless-camera/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s almost Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day, and, long story short, I volunteered to run a &amp;ldquo;photobooth&amp;rdquo; for my kid&amp;rsquo;s school class party. The props and backdrop were easy enough, but who really wants to use an expensive Polaroid-type film camera these days? So I cooked up another solution. What if I could use a digital camera, transfer photos wirelessly to my laptop and display them in an almost real-time slideshow on a large screen that the classroom already had?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cscope - 64 bit vs 32 bit</title>
      <link>https://akent.org/posts/cscope-64-bit-vs-32-bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 09:49:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akent.org/posts/cscope-64-bit-vs-32-bit/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a fun Cscope error message:
E609: Cscope error: cscope: invlib.c:566: invopen: Assertion `invcntl-aram.sizeblk == sizeof(t_logicalblk)&#39; failed.
Long story short: don&amp;rsquo;t try to use cscope files on a 32 bit machine if they were generated on a 64 bit machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foursquare and Google Calendar</title>
      <link>https://akent.org/posts/foursquare-and-google-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 08:29:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akent.org/posts/foursquare-and-google-calendar/</guid>
      <description>A good use for foursquare: Go to http://foursquare.com/feeds/ and copy the URL for the ICS feed. Now go to Google Calendar, find the &amp;ldquo;Other Calendars&amp;rdquo; box on the lower left corner and click the &amp;ldquo;Add&amp;rdquo; link on the bottom right corner of that box. Select &amp;ldquo;Add by URL&amp;rdquo; and paste in the Foursquare ICS URL. Now your Foursquare checkins show up in Google Calendar, reminding you where you&amp;rsquo;ve been and what you&amp;rsquo;ve done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideal things to look for in a laptop</title>
      <link>https://akent.org/posts/ideal-things-to-look-for-in-a-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 14:46:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akent.org/posts/ideal-things-to-look-for-in-a-laptop/</guid>
      <description>Regardless of physical dimensions, a fine dot pitch display. My current screen is a 15&amp;quot; normal (non-widescreen) display SXGA+ which has been great. That works out at about 116 DPI or a 0.2177mm dot pitch. It&amp;rsquo;s well worth whatever it costs extra to get a good built in display. Screen DPI calculator. No shiny / reflective display finishes. Quite simply, a deal breaker. I hate those shiny screens. Built in serial port.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The problem with photography</title>
      <link>https://akent.org/posts/the-problem-with-photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2009 15:17:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akent.org/posts/the-problem-with-photography/</guid>
      <description>What, then, is so wrong with the camera? Nothing, thought Ruskin initially&amp;hellip; Yet Ruskin&amp;rsquo;s enthusiasm diminished as he observed the devilish problem that photography created for the majority of its practitioners. Rather than using photography as a supplement to active, conscious seeing, they used it as an alternative, playing less attention to the world than they had done previously from a faith that photography automatically assured them posession of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arial or Helvetica</title>
      <link>https://akent.org/posts/arial-or-helvetica/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2005 09:22:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akent.org/posts/arial-or-helvetica/</guid>
      <description>Think you know your typefaces? Take the ultimate typeface quiz, and try to distinguish between Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Arial font and the nearly identical Helvetica. I got six out of ten on a cold first go, so there are definitely tell tale signs. No cheating now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fig leaves</title>
      <link>https://akent.org/posts/fig-leaves/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2005 13:11:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akent.org/posts/fig-leaves/</guid>
      <description>At the door I hop about, trying to pick the stupid things off. I fall over. I get some of the leaves I have removed on my trousers. A couple I have flicked away are now stuck to a window. The tree is turning my life into a slapstick routine. I stump morosely inside, my feet sticking lightly to the carpet with each step, and open a beer.
It&amp;rsquo;s not quite as bad as all that but still, for some reason, the Moreton Bay Figs are annoying me more than usual this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Since U Been Gone Powerpoint</title>
      <link>https://akent.org/posts/since-u-been-gone-powerpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2005 13:29:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akent.org/posts/since-u-been-gone-powerpoint/</guid>
      <description>The web is a crazy place.
Kelly Clarkson set to corporate slideware. Since U Been Gone Annual Report 2005 and since-youve-been-gone.pps.
UPDATE: Original site down, archived copy.
See also www.clicktoaddtitle.com.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASCII Art Spam</title>
      <link>https://akent.org/posts/ascii-art-spam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2005 04:52:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akent.org/posts/ascii-art-spam/</guid>
      <description>Found in my inbox: (yes, it snuck past my spam filter!) A creative way to get attention if nothing else&amp;hellip;
., ,; .r, @kr sik awl pg kt, Bdc hlB WvW iftswgu: inwgkWvc Wkcrhb @leeqcS li mo pgg tx wl. Wwk. std yxw dn; @iS tjn gmx WbW 8cwhhp: hw ja WoZ Zbtftn@ kq .if WlW ydW:: kt, xr ca WgW tnp,i 0dW SmutkS WqW qq uc qkZ rhj WgW sqB 0wZ snqy swb lsqqefpjy ggcWemyb xet feapjlkpx0 , ,:;i : mr , ,;i .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pyrmont Hellhole</title>
      <link>https://akent.org/posts/pyrmont-hellhole/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2005 12:41:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akent.org/posts/pyrmont-hellhole/</guid>
      <description>Quite close to where I’m working right now in Pyrmont are three curious sandstone blocks, one of which has “Hellhole” carved into it. I have long wondered what this was all about; my best guess ‘til now was that it was just some random outdoor art installation. In retrospect it’s obvious… The area around Pyrmont used to be home to three sandstone quarries, known as Hellhole, Paradise and Purgatory.
The quarries were named according to the relative difficulty in extracting sandstone from them, as well as the quality of the stone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect Four and the Minimax algorithm</title>
      <link>https://akent.org/posts/connect-four-and-the-minimax-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2004 14:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akent.org/posts/connect-four-and-the-minimax-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>A good implementation of the game Connect Four done in javascript with a more-than-competent computer AI player, implemented with a minimax algorithm. Unfortunately it only runs in Internet Explorer. It&amp;rsquo;s part of the WebFX site, which features all sorts of nifty DHTML and javascript toys and menus.
Playing the actual game against a real live opponent is decidedly more fun than being consistently (well, 75% of the time) beaten by the computer, though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomatoes aren&#39;t the only non-fruit</title>
      <link>https://akent.org/posts/tomatoes-arent-the-only-non-fruit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2004 01:47:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://akent.org/posts/tomatoes-arent-the-only-non-fruit/</guid>
      <description>This little rant was posted on the Triple J Breakfast Show guestbook today for &amp;ldquo;tell it like it is Friday&amp;rdquo;:
I&amp;rsquo;d like to &amp;ldquo;tell it like it is&amp;rdquo; about people who go to great pains to point out that a tomato is a fruit. I know it is a fruit. If it developed from a flower its a fruit. But why single out the tomato? You never hear this conversation&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
